ALEKSEI GRIGOREV

EU, UK · +385 99 2022511 · hello@agrigorev.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/a-grigorev/

SUMMARY

Product Design Manager with 12 years of experience in digital design (iOS, Android, Web) across various business domains: FinTech, Classifieds, Travel, Corp. Software (B2B, SaaS), and Digital Media. Designed and executed user-centered product strategies for major projects aimed at acquiring new customers. Effectively mentored and developed designers of all levels. Focused on the design thinking process, human-centered design principles, and advocating for the value of design. **'The Glue' between business, product, and users.**

EXPERIENCE

Art Director (Sr. Product Design Manager)

Jul 2022 - present

Alfa Bank / Moscow, Russia

The largest private bank with 6.3 mln active digital clients

- Conceptualized, designed, and executed the product design strategy for integrating banking services into VK Messenger (56.3 million active users), resulting in +275,000 new active users per month
- Designed and executed a user-centered product strategy for the Alfa Bank mobile application for kids, resulting in over 300,000 new parents as customers
- Successfully led a major redesign of Alfa Bank's mobile app, which reduced the completion time of key tasks by 20%

Product Design Manager (Principal Product Designer)

2020 - 2022

Yandex LLC / Moscow, Russia

Top tech company in Europe $\approx 21~000$ *employees*

- Organized and successfully implemented a user research process at Auto.ru (product DAU 4 mln)
- Designed and integrated a Competency Map for product designers of all levels at Auto.ru, which made the process of designers' growth transparent
- Conceptualized and executed a cutting-edge 360-degree panorama design for listings, resulting in a 40% increase in engagement and viewing of car cards (selling time reduced by 12%)

Senior Product Designer

2017 - 2020

Yandex LLC / Moscow, Russia

Top tech company in Europe $\approx 21~000$ *employees*

- Conceptualized and designed the offer posting form, reducing the time required for completion from 30 to 15 minutes
- Elevated brand recognition and boosted website traffic by designing Mag.Auto.ru, Russia's premier digital media about cars
- Revolutionized the listing UX/UI, leading to a reduced response time by 15% and an increase in loan applications by 8%

EDUCATION

- British Higher School of Art and Design Interactive Design and New Media / Moscow, Russia, 2014
- Moscow State Institute of Radio Engineering, Electronics and Automation Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering / Moscow, Russia, 2011

SKILLS

Product Design, Art Direction, Design Leadership, User-Centered Design, Design Strategy, Cross-Functional Collaboration, Design Management, UX/UI Expertise, Creative Direction, Design Thinking, Team Management, Product Innovation, Design Operations, Design Vision, Mentorship, Stakeholder Management, Mobile Application Design, iOS/Android Guidelines, Startup Launch, Web Design, User Research.